Guide to the Elmer E. Robinson Americana, 1765-1950 M0002
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Elmer E. Robinson Americana,
1765-1950
M0002
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
1.75 Linear feet
Robinson, Elmer E. (Elmer Edwin), b. 1894
Materials Withdrawn From the Collection
All imprints were transferred to the Robinson Room as books. A British Protectorate ordinance, dated 1653, was catalogued in the K scheme of the Bender Room.
All newspapers were filed with the Early American Newspaper Collection.
Miscellaneous periodicals were plated with the Elmer E. Robinson tab. Those issues complementing existing holdings were cataloged in the Special Collections holdings. All other issues were placed in a locked cabinet in the Robinson Room.
Also removed to Felton cabinet with other literary manuscripts were:
Markham, Edwin:
Lincoln, the Man of the People (sgd. broadside).
A Ward for Mother's Day (2 pp. holograph poem).
Imprints
1. Allen, Thaddeus. An Inquiry: The Founders Of Our Union And Government. Boston, 1845. 86 pp.
2. Bayard, Thomas F., Speech of. Ku Klux Organization. Washinton, 1871. 24 pp.
3. Beck, James B., Speech of. Postal Telegraph. Washington, 1872. 23 pp.
4. Benedict, E. C., Speech of. The War. Albany, 1864. 16 pp.
5. Bond, Speech of. Upon Mr. Hopkins' Resolution To Divorce The Government From The Press. Richmond, 1833. 35 pp.
6. Brown B. Gratz, Speech of. The Reform Movement. Washington, 1872. 8 pp.
7. Calhoun, John C., Speech of. Resolutions In Reference To The War With Mexico. Washington, 1848.
8. The Code of 1650. San Francisco. 119 pp.
9. Daveis, Charles Stewart, Address of. On the Decease of John Adams and Thomas Jefferson. Portland, 1826. 55pp.
10. Disney, D.T., Speech of. The Disposition Of The Public Domain. Washington, 1854. 15 pp.
11. Winslow, Warren, Speech of. Assault On Senator Sumner. Washington, 1856. 8 pp.
12. Douglas, Stephen A. An American Continental Commercial Union Or Alliance. Second Edition. Washington, 1889. 36 pp.
13. England. (Protectorate) An Ordinance For alternation of several Names and Forms.... London, 1653. 8 pp.
14. Everett, Edward, Speech of. On The Proposition To Amend The Constitution. Boston, 1826. 38 pp.
15. Garfield, James A. Tested and Sustained... Reply To Attacks Upon His Offical Character. 1874. 16 pp.
16. Hamilton, Alexander. (pseudon. Phocion) The Federalist. Philadelphia, 1796. 48 pp.
17. Hamilton William T., Speech of. The Tariff. Washington, 1872. 13 pp.
18. Harcourt, W.G.G.V. (pseudon. Historicus) American Neutrality. New York, 1865. 11 pp.
19. Jackson, Andrew. Farewell Address To People Of The United States. Washington, 1837. 23 pp.
20 Jefferson, Thomas, Message from. Information Touching An Illegal Combination...Against The Peace and Safety Of the Union.... 1807. 16 pp.
21. Lowell, J. Candid Comparison Of The Principles And Conduct Of The Washington And Jefferson Administrations. Boston, 1810. 148 pp.
22. Lee Henry. Funeral Oration On The Death of General Washington. Boston, 1800. 15 pp.
23. Massachusetts, Abstract of District Attorneys' Reports. 1845. 25 pp.
24. Moore, C.C. Observations Upon Certain Passages In Mr. Jefferson's Notes On Virginia, Which Appear To Have A Tendency To Subvert Religion, And Establish A False Philosophy. New York, 1804. 32 pp.
25. Morrill, L.M., Speech of. Confiscation Of Property. 1862. 16 pp.
26. Morris, Gouverneur, Oration of. In Celebration Of the Recent Deliverance Of Europe From the Yoke Of Military Despotism. New York, 1814. 23 pp.
27. Newport Mercury. Important State Papers. 1809. 40 pp.
28. New Washinton or The Renovated Capital City. Washinton, 1874. 26 pp.
29. Nott, Eliphalet. A Discourse On The Death Of Gen. Alexander Hamilton. Boston, 1805. 24 pp.
30. Otis, Harrison G. Eulogy On General Alexander Hamilton. New York, 1804. 23 pp.
31. Pearce, Franklin. The Politics Of The Day. 1856. 8 pp.
32. Pickering, Timothy. A Review Of the Correspondence Between The Hon. John Adams...And The Late Wm. Cunningham, Esq. Salem, 1824. 197 pp.
33. The Politician's Register For 1841. Sixth Edition. New York, 1841. 60 pp.
34. Schurz, Carl. Annexation Of San Domingo. Washington, 1871. 20 pp.
35. Shellabarger, S., Speech of. Reconstruction. Washington, 1866. 8 pp.
36. Scofield, Glenni W., Speech of. Suffrage In the District Of Columbia. Washington, 1866. 8 pp.
37. Slidell, John, Speech of. Suspension Of The Neutrality Laws. Washington, 1854. 7 pp.
38. Stille, Charles J. How A Free People Conduct A Long War. New York. 16 pp.
39. Stillman, J.D.B., Speech of. California Pioneers. San Francisco, 1874. 47 pp.
40. Sumner, Charles, Speech of. Ransom Of Slaves At The National Capital. Washington, 1862. 13 pp.
41. Sumner, Charles, Speech of. Indemnity For The Past And Security For The Future. Washington, 1862. 16 pp.
42. Sumner, Charles, Speech of. Reform and Purity in Government--Neutral Duties. Sale of Arms to Belligerent France. Washington, 1872. 15 pp.
43. Sumner, Charles, Speech of. The Rebellion: Its Origin and Main-Spring. 1861. 16 pp.
44. Sutherland, J., Speech of. The Homestead Bill. Washington, 1852. 21 pp.
45. Trumbull, Lyman, Speech of. Republicanism--Not Partisanship. Washington, 1872. 19 pp.
46. United States. Report Of the Committee on Pensions and Revolutionary Claims on the Petition of Elizabeth Hamilton. 1816. 3 pp.
47. Webster, Daniel. Discourse In Commemoration Of The Lives and Services Of John Adams And Thomas Jefferson. Boston, 1826. 62 pp.
48. The Whig Almanac And United States Register For 1843. New York, 1843. 64 pp.
49. Wood, Fernando, Speech of. Confiscation. Washington, 1864. 8 pp.
50. Constitution of the United States--Art Type Edition
51. Declaration of Independence--Art Type Edition
Newspapers
Maryland Journal of Baltimore Advertiser. Baltimore, August 20, 1773
New-Jersey Gazette. New-Jersey, April 29, 1779
Massachusetts Centinel. Boston, June 10, 1789
The Salem Mercury. Salem, Mass., October 2, 1787
Pennsylvania Journal and Weekly Advertiser. Philadelphia, October 3, 1787
Pennsylvania Mercuryand Universal Advertiser. Philadelphia, October 12, 1787
Connecticut Courant and Weekly Intelligencer. Hartford, November 20, 1781
Boston Post-Boy &C. Boston, November 4, 1765
Extraordinary
Continental Journal and Weekly Advertiser. Boston, January 4, 1781
Saturday Evening Post. Philadelphia, September 8, 1827
Hartford Daily Courant. Hartford, April 17, 1865
The Boston. News-Letter (facsimile). Boston, April 17-24, 1704
Old Countryman; or Emigrants Journal. New York, February 8, 1840
Old Countryman; or Emigrants Journal. New York, February 15, 1840
Old Countryman; or Emigrants Journal. New York, February 22, 1840
Old Countryman; or Emigrants Journal. New York, February 29, 1840
Old Countryman; or Emigrants Journal. New York, March 7, 1840
Old Countryman; or Emigrants Journal. New York, March 14, 1840
The Evening Gazette. New York, August 12, 1845
Pictorial Town Talk (Steamer Edition). San Francisco, June 5, 1856
Sacramento Daily Union. Sacramento, August 30, 1860
Scientific Press. San Francisco, April 27, 1872
The Courier-Journal. Louisville, October 4, 1876
Ocean Chronicle. On Board Ship, November 1, 1882
California Political Record. San Francisco, June 3, 1882
The Daily Examiner. San Francisco, March 4, 1887
The Examiner. San Francisco, June 25, 1893
Call-Chronicle-Examiner. San Francisco, April 19, 1906
San Francisco Examiner. San Francisco, June 29, 1914
S.F. Chronicle (Memento). San Francisco, April 23, 1880 (2 copies)
Fraternal Record. San Francisco, December, 1886
Harper's Weekly. New York, September 21, 1901
Arthur McEwen's Letter. San Francisco, June 1, 1895
News Letter. San Francisco, December 1, 1866
News Letter. San Francisco, December 23, 1871
News Letter. San Francisco, September 26, 1874
News Letter. San Francisco, March 1, 1879
News Letter. San Francisco, June 7, 1884
News Letter. San Francisco, October 15, 1887
News Letter. San Francisco, August 22, 1891
News Letter. San Francisco, February 11, 1893
Signs of the Times. Mt. View, Calif., May 2, 1906 (S.F. Earthquake Special)
The Argonaut. San Francisco, December 13, 1879
The Argonaut. San Francisco, November 29, 1884
The Argonaut. San Francisco, March 17, 1890
City Argus. San Francisco, February 7, 1885
City Argus. San Francisco, June 4, 1887
City Argus. San Francisco, August 11, 1894
City Argus. San Francisco, June 6, 1896
City Argus. San Francisco, January 16, 1897
City Argus. San Francisco, March 6, 1897
City Argus. San Francisco, March 5, 1898
City Argus. San Francisco, January 13, 1900
Illustrated London News. London, June 26, 1858
Illustrated London News. London, July 4, 1863
Illustrated London News. London, February 17, 1872
The Wasp. San Francisco, August 25, 1883
The Wasp. San Francisco, January 29, 1881
The Wasp. San Francisco, August 20, 1887
The Wasp. San Francisco, August 4, 1888
The Wasp. San Francisco, March 15, 1890
The Wasp. San Francisco, May 24, 1890
The Wasp. San Francisco, May 16, 1891
The Wasp. San Francisco, April 16, 1892
The Wasp. San Francisco, February 18, 1893
The Wasp. San Francisco, April 7, 1894
The Wasp. San Francisco, March 30, 1895
The Wasp. San Francisco, June, 1898
The Wasp. San Francisco, October, 1899
The Wasp. San Francisco, September 15, 1900
The Wasp San Francisco, September 21, 1901
The Wasp San Francisco, September 13, 1902
The Wasp San Francisco, December, 1904
The Wasp San Francisco, February 6, 1908
The Wasp San Francisco, March 20, 1909
The Wasp San Francisco, March 27, 1909
The Wasp San Francisco, July 31, 1909
The Wasp San Francisco, August 21, 1909
The Wasp San Francisco, September 4, 1909
The Wasp San Francisco, May 13, 1916
The Wave San Francisco, August 8, 1891
The Wave San Francisco, February 20, 1892
The Wave San Francisco, May 14, 1892
The Wave San Francisco, May 27, 1893
The Wave San Francisco, November 4, 1893
The Wave San Francisco, October 24, 1896
The Wave San Francisco, June 11, 1898
The Wave San Francisco, November 9, 1901
Town Talk San Francisco, February 25, 1899
Town Talk San Francisco, June 24, 1899
Town Talk San Francisco, October 18, 1902
Town Talk San Francisco, September 20, 1902
Town Talk San Francisco, June 13, 1903
Town Talk San Francisco, August 19, 1905
Town Talk San Francisco, August 3, 1907
The Western Empire Los Angeles, October, 1895 (Oakland edition)
Western World San Francisco, July 13, 1907
The Western Soldier San Francisco, September, 1891
Overland Monthly San Francisco, March, 1903
Overland Monthly San Francisco, October, 1929
The New-York Mirror New York, March 30, 1833
Scope and Content
Correspondence, documents, photographs, early American newspapers, and printed matter. Includes documents signed by George Washington and 27 other U.S. presidents, government officials, and seven early California Governors. Correspondents include William Jennings Bryan, Hamilton Fish, eight U.S. presidents, and other American government, civilian and military figures. Lithograph portraits with facsimile signatures of all the presidents from George Washington through Buchanan. Photographs with autographs of all the presidents from Abraham Lincoln through Eisenhower with the exception of President Arthur.
Provenance
Gift of Elmer E. Robinson, 1959.
Access Restrictions
None.
- CORRESPONDENCE OF AMERICAN GOVERNMENT, CIVILIAN AND MILITARY FIGURES., 1778-1941.
  Scope and Contents note
  Almost wholly letters sent.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by name of sender.
  - ADAMS, CHARLES F., (1) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1932, Feb. 25.
  - ADAMS, JOHN., (2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - DS (warrant)., 1765, Oct.
  - ADAMS, JOHN QUINCY, (22) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - DS. Appointment of Thomas Thruston as clerk in Dept. of State., 1818, May 7.
    - to Robert F. Paine re right of petition; slavery. Also a typescript with explanatory memo., 1845, March 29.; ALS
  - AMES, FISHER, (4) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - AL to [Alexander Hamilton?]. Portrait.
  - AMUNDSEN, ROALD, (2) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Photostat of cable to [King and Queen of Norway] in Norwegian with typed translation., 1912, [March 7?].
  - ARTHUR, CHESTER A., (1) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Signature on Executive Mansion stationery and note., 1882, March 2.
  - BACHE, HARTMAN [Brig. Gen.], (2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - to C.W. Lawrence., 1846, July 17.; ALS
  - BADEAU, ADAM [Brig. Gen.], (2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - to Mrs. Sykes., [1877], Dec. 21.; ALS
  - BANCROFT, GEORGE [1800-1891], (1) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Signed check., 1867, Nov. 25.
  - BANKHEAD, HENRY C., (2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - LS to Second Auditor, U.S. Treasury sending return of deceased soldiers., 1867, Aug. 26.
  - BANKS, NATHANIEL PRENTISS [1816-1894] [Maj. Gen.], (2) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - to James Redpath., 1874, Jan. 12.; ALS
  - BRADFORD, WILLIAM, JR. [1755-1795], (1) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - to J. Nicholson., 1788, March 22.; ANS
  - BRANDEIS, LOUIS D., (3) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - TLcS Philos Cooke to LDB., 1936, March 17.
    - to Philos Cooke., 1936, March 29.; ANS
  - BRYAN, WILLIAM JENNINGS (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - AL to David Starr Jordan. Cuban intervention, etc., 1900, Feb. 19.
      General note
      TRANSFERRED TO JORDAN PAPERS, UNIVERSITY ARCHIVES. BRYAN, WILLIAM JENNINGS
  - BRYAN, WILLIAM JENNINGS, (3)
    - DS Printed invitation to National Education Assn. to Second Pan-American Scientific Congress., 1915, Feb. 12.
    - to Mr. Merrill., 1917, Dec. 26.; ALS
  - CAMERON, SIMON, (1) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - to A. Lincoln., 1864, April 27.; ALS
  - CARDOZO, BENJAMIN N., (1) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1932, Feb. 20.
  - CARNEGIE, ANDREW, (1) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - to Mr. Sutro., 1892, March 9.; ALS
  - CHASE, SALMON P., (3) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - to Franklin Haven re: Johnson's impeachment; inc. xerox copy and note on a cover re above., 1868, May 26.; ALS
  - CHOATE, JOSEPH H., (1) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - to Frederick S. Wait., 1897, March 23.; ALS
  - CLEVELAND, S. GROVER, (6) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - cvr. to Mrs. Dickinson., 1892, Feb. 28. &; ALS
    - Facs. to William Baldenwick and [?]., 1893, May 10.; ALS
  - COOLIDGE, CALVIN, (4) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Facs. to David Lawrence. -- from publisher of facsimile., 1926, Oct. 2.; 2 pp. TLS ALS
    - to Robert E. Swain., 1930, Feb. 18.; TLS
  - CURTIN, ANDREW GREGG, (2) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - to Louis Sloss., 1883, Jan. 21.; ALS
  - DANIELS, JOSEPHUS, (1) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - to Dr. & Mrs. R.L. Wilbur., 1935, March 26.; TLS
  - DARROW, CLARENCE, (4) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - to Mrs. Bernard DeVoto., 1925, Jan. 21.; TLS
    - to E.H. Lewis., 1930, Sept. 15.; ALS
    - E.H. Lewis to Darrow., 1930, Sept. 19.; ALS
    - TL, Darrow's secy. to [Lewis]., 1935, Jan. 22.
  - DAVIS, DWIGHT F., (1) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1930, Jan. 17.; TLS
  - DAVIS, JAMES J., (1) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1929, Dec. 16.; TLS
  - DAVIS, JEFFERSON, (3) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - to Albert Greenleaf re Franklin Pierce., 1887, June 6.; ALS
    - by J. Harris PC photo of Davis. [Transferred from Special Collections - RB], 1894, Dec. 31 ©
  - DAWES, CHARLES G., (2) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1929, March 16.; TLS
    - to R.L. Wilbur.re Barbara Hutton., 1931, Jan. 16.; TLS
  - DEPEW, CHAUNCEY M., (1) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - to David Pell Secor., 1895, Dec. 28.; ANS
  - DOAK, WILLIAM NUCKLES, (1) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1931, Dec. 21.
  - DRINKARD, W. N., (3) (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - cvr. to Snow and Bradstreet., 1857, Oct. 31. &; ALS
  - DUNCAN, JAMES M., (2) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - to Andrew Johnson., 1866, Aug. 24.; ALS
  - EDWARDS, DON, (30) (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - (some autopen) dated re Vietnam, Adam Clayton Powell, US concentration camps, and the Selective Service, addressedto Mrs. Lorna B. Smith. [Some ephemera.], 1965-68; 17 TLS
  - FARRAGUT, VIRGINIA LOYALL [1824-], (23) (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 7-31; chron. of D. G. Farragut., 1866:
    - 3-9; obit. of VLF; 7-28; 8-23; 9-5; 9-26; 12-2; 12-4., 1867:
    - 1-7; 4-3; 4-22; 4-27; 6-24; 10-13., 1868:
      Typed carbons and original letters to Camilla, Linnie and Loyall.
  - FILLMORE, MILLARD, (3) (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - to Lathrop Cooke., 1849, April 28.; ALS
    - to U.S. Treasurer re salary., 1850, Nov. 7.; ALS
    - LS to G.F. Adams. [mounted and typed note.], 1851, Feb. 10.
  - FISH, HAMILTON [1808-1893], (1) (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - to Henry T. Drevin., 1880, Dec. 22.; ALS
  - FISHER, T. H. [Capt.], (1) (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - DS. Circular orders re review by Gen. Grant., 1864, March 29.
  - FORT, GREENBURY L. [Col.], (1) (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - to General. Vicksburg, leaving for New Orleans by ship., 1864, Feb. 2.; ANS
  - FOSTER, BENJAMIN B., (3) (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Signed voucher or receipt., 1864, April [3].
  - FULLER, SARAH A., (2) (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - to James Buchanan., 1860, Oct. 13.; ALS
    - Endorsement on verso by James Buchanan., 1860, Oct. 16.
  - GARFIELD, JAMES A., (1) (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - to Clarence King., 1881, March 15.; ALS
  - GILLETT, FRANK, (1) (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - to Major R.R. Towns re case of George A. Dunham., 1863, Sept. 3.; ALS
  - GODDARD, CALVIN [Adj. Gen.], (1) (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - ADS. Spec. Orders to Gen. McPherson from Gen. Rosecrans. Breaking up troops under hisc command., 1862
  - GOMEZ, MIGUEL MARIANO, (2) (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1929, Dec. 21.; TLS
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1936, Jan. 22.; TLS
  - GRANT, ULYSSES SIMPSON, (6) (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - LS to Lt. Henry Prince forwarding orders from Col. W. Whistler. Inside from John Garland to Prince., 1847, Jan. 10. 1847, Feb. 26.; ANS
    - ADS. Invoice in dup. of horse turned over to Lt. Prince., 1847, Aug. 1.
    - to Gen. Meade., 1864, Aug. 26.; ANS
    - Signed check to Louis Weber., 1866, Geb. 16.
  - GREELEY, HORACE, (1) (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - to [Latvo]., 1871, Oct. 15.; ANS
  - HANNA, MARCUS A., (1) (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - TLStto A. R. Smith., 1896, March 21.
  - HAVEN, FRANKLIN, (26) (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - cvr. to Horace P. Chandler., 1884, Aug. 18. &; ALS
    - to unknown & partial copy of Chase letter by Haven., N.D.; ANS
    - Century reprint: Impeachment of Andrew Johnson., 1913 -
  - HOOVER, HERBERT CLARK, (3) (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - to Mark L. Requa (mtd.), 1932, Aug. 10.; TLS
    - to Thomas Rolph., 1940, Aug. 25.; TLS
    - to Mrs. Andrew Stewart., 1948, Nov. 26.; TLS
  - HUGHES, CHARLES EVANS, (3) (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - to Guido H. Marx., 1908, Nov. 16.; TLS
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1930, Feb. 6.; TLS
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1941, Jan. 28.; TLS
  - HULL, CORDELL, (1) (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1936, Oct. 12.; TLS
  - HUNTINGTON, EBENEZER, [Gen.], (1) (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - to Joshua Huntington reporting enemy losses. (with auction note)., 1778, Sept. 30.; ALS
  - HURLEY, PATRICK J., (2) (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1929, Dec. 18.
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1932, Eeb. 9.
  - HYDE, ARTHUR M., (1) (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1931, Dec. 21.
  - JACKSON, ANDREW, (4) (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - LS to James K. Baulding., 1830, Jan. 7.
    - to John M. Niles, with exhibit caption. Mentions the divorce bill., 1838, Jan. 24.; ALS
  - JAHNCKE, ERNEST LEE, (1) (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1931, Dec. 21.; TLS
  - JAY, JOHN, (3) (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - LS to James Watson. Fortifications of NY harbor and Governor's Island. Portrait., 1798, May 15.
  - JEFFERSON, THOMAS, (3) (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - to John Griscom & cvr., 1824, April 3.; ALS
    - [facs.] to Craven. Peyton., 1803, Nov. 27.; ALS
  - KELLY, EDWARD J., (1) (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1939, Aug. 16.; TLS
  - KENDALL, AMOS, (3) (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - to Andrew Jackson., 1830, Jan. 5.; ALS
  - [KUHLER, HEINZ L.], (13) (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Typed notes of German ambassador's speech before the Steuben Society. Signed., 1953, Sept. 12.
  - LAFAYETTE, GILBERT DU MOTIER, MARQUIS DE, (1) (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - to M. St. Albin., 1823; ALS
  - LAFAYETTE, GEORGE WASHINGTON, (1) (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - to M. Ganneron and translation., --, March 23.; ANS
  - LAMONT, ROBERT PATTERSON, (2) (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1929, Dec. 18.
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1931, Dec. 21.
  - LEDERER, FRANCIS, (3) (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - cvr. to Mrs. Sloss., N.D. &; ALS
  - LINDBERGH, CHARLES A., (1) (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1931, May 27.; TLS
  - LODGE, HENRY CABOT, (1) (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - to E.L. Plumb., 1901, March 9.; TLS
  - McADOO, WILLIAM GIBBS, (2) (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - to R.L. Wilbur., 1925, Dec. 16.; TLS
    - to P. W. Thompson., 1932, Nov. 16.; TLS
  - MacVEAGH, WAYNE, (2) (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - to L.P. Marston., 1882, May 10.; ALS
  - MADISON, JAMES, (1) (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - DS Land conveyance James Monroe to John Zimmerman., 1812, March 3.
  - MARCY, W. L., (1) (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - to A. Campbell., [?], Jan. 14.; ANS
  - MARSHALL, THOMAS R., (2) (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - cvr. to George Barnett., 1917, May 19. &; TLS
  - MASON, JOHN Y., (1) (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - DS Orders to Edward C. Grafton., 1844, Oct. 3.
  - MAYNARD, HORACE, (1) (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - A. Draft(fin.)S. to [James W. M. O'Henry]., 1860, June 14.
  - MELLON, ANDREW W., (1) (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1931, Dec. 19.
  - MELVILLE, GEORGE, (2) (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - to David Munro., 1903, Feb. 12.; TLS
  - MEREDITH, WILLIAM M., (2) (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - LS to J. Purviance re Bank of Pennsylvania., 1850, Jan. 5.
  - MILLS, OGDEN L., (1) (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1934, May 31.
  - MITCHELL, WILLIAM D., (1) (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - TNS to R.L. Wilbur., 1929, Dec. 19.
  - MORRILL, JUSTIN S., (2) (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - DS Conclusion of speech on military power., 1866, May 8.
  - MORTON, LEVI P., (1) (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - to Clarence W. Bower., 1894, Oct. 17.; TLS
  - MURPHY, FRANCIS, (2) (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - to Mr. Mumford., 1883, Oct. 8.; ANS
  - NIXON, RICHARD M., (2) (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Photostat and original cover to Spencer Bickerton., 1955, April 18.; TLS
  - PAUL I, KING OF GREECE, (15) (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Sgd. TS of speech to Press and Union League Club., 1953, Nov. 10.
  - PAVLOVA, ANNA autograph., (1) (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - PEARY, R. E. autograph., (1) (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - PERSHING, JOHN J., (1) (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - to R. L. Wilbur., 1939, Nov. 16.; TLS
  - PETTIT, CHARLES, (4) (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - to Samuel Tucker & cvr. Moving official papers of New Jersey; appearance of British fleet off Sandy Hook; confusion on orders. [Exhibit caption enclosed.], 1776, July 1.; ALS
  - PICKERING, TIMOTHY, (2) (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - to Thomas Barclay. [With auction notes and caption.], 1799, July 9.; ALS
  - POLK, JAMES KNOX, (2) (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - to Jesse Miller [with auction notes and caption.], 1844, July 3.; ALS
  - PROXMIRE, WILLIAM, (1) (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - to Govt. Docs., Stanford U., 1972, May 17.; TLS
  - RANDOLPH, EDMUND, (2) (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - ALStto William Bell. Trial of the Cyrus at Williamsburg. [caption], 1788, July 21.
  - RANDOLPH, JOHN, (2) (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - to Richard Randolph, sgd. J. R. of Roanoke., 1826, Dec. 27.; ALS
      -- Sgd, engraved portrait.
  - ROCKEFELLER, JOHN D. JR., (1) (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - to R. L. Wilbur., 1933, Feb. 28.; TLS
  - ROOSEVELT, FRANKLIN D., (4) (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - to P.W. Thompson. [from Weiss oak cabinet.], 1932, Dec. 9.; TLS
    - TL sgd. by secy. [form letter]., [1932?].
    - Louis M. H. Howe [pvt. secy.] to R. L. Wilbur., 1933, Feb. 10.
    - to E. D. Cobleitz., 1933, March 13.; TLS
  - ROOSEVELT, THEODORE, (1) (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - to S.F. Surveyor of Customs. Signed as acting President of the US Civil Service Commission., 1893, Aug. 16.; TLS
  - ROOT, ELIHU, (1) (Box 2, Folder 97)